

PROFILE

Award winning masters qualified General Manager, with an exemplary career within hospitality spanning the last 15 years including Kempinski Hotels, Acoor, Hilton and Landmark group across the Middle East.

Utilizing my passion for hospitality and customer service. I have achieved numerous promotions into roles of progressive responsibility. I am a GM that has worked his way up through the ranks across numerous departments- Front of House, Operations and expert Food and Beverage. As a net result, I bring allround capability within hotel management, as well as the ability to identify and implement improvements that enhance productivity, engage employees and transform customer experience, that is reflected by excellent track record of service improvements and incremental revenue generation in every role I have held to date.

CONTACT

PHONE: +971528955227 Address: United Arab Emirates, Ras Al Khaimah

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmadtaher-mba-2582642a

EMAIL:

Ahmad taher82@yahoo.com

AHMAD TAHER

MULTI PROPERTY GENERAL MANAGER

EDUCATION

University of Northampton UK

2015 to 2017

Master of Business Administration. Awarded 180 credits at level 7, Classification Merit.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Landmark Group, Citymax Hotels, General Manager (Multi property) Citymax Ras Al Khaimah and Citymax Hotels Egypt.

July 2015 – to date

Operationally leading a 204-Keys Hotel in Ras Al Khaimah fully setup with enhanced F&B outlets. Two hotels in Aswan City, Egypt, 102-Keys and 165 Keys. Responsible of full P&L and Budget up to \$6.2m. Direct reporting to the CEO and Board of Directors.

- Oversight Front office, F&B, HK, Engineering and over all full hotel operation with a focus on customer service, appearance and adherence to group SOPs.
- Ensure to develop an effective, cohesive & competent team.
- Monitor and maximize the profitability of all departments.
- Ensure continued conformity to all Health & Safety, HACCP and legislative requirements.

Pre-Opening General Manager & Head of F&B. Mar 2017 to Oct 2017 (Pre-opening of Three properties)

- Managing the opening three properties (Egypt, Dubai and RAK) in addition, managing all aspects of F&B operation across 7 properties
- Leading all task force team for pre-opening activities of the new hotels (Business bay, Ras Al Khaimah, within UAE).
 Additionally, overseas and responsible for Citymax Hotel Aswan in (Egypt).
- Leading all F&B functions and developments across Citymax Hotels portfolio.

Director of Food & Beverage Jul 2015 to Mar 2017

 Managing and coordinate the Food & Beverage operations of 9 food and beverage outlets (Asian Restaurant, authentic west Indian Restaurant, Lobby Cafe, All Day Dining, one of the best Sports Bars in Dubai, Huddle Sports Bar & Grill, Pool Bar, Room Service, Outside catering and home delivery

USFUL LINKS AND AWARDS

- Guinness world record holder for the longest domino drop shot in the world https://www.youtube.com/w atch?v=QwAxnSjB-ts.
- F&B manager of the year 2017 and Hotel Team of the year (Hoteliers express award Middle East)
 http://www.hoteliermiddleeast.com/hotelier-awards/food-beverage/
- Shortlisted one of top 5 F&B Managers in Hoteliers Award Middle East 2014, http://edition.pagesuiteprofessional.co.uk//launch.as px?eid=8b9b597c-07cd-4987b363-d0372b10684a
 Fage 53.
- Golden medal in table setting competition 30-oct-2007 with the (international hospitality forum 2007 exhibition.
- Star Team of the year (all day dining team) Kempinski Ishtar dead sea 2008.



Director of Food and Beverage Warwick International Hotels Sep 2014 – Jul 2015

- Warwick Fiji Resort, Director of Food & Beverage Sep 2014 Jan 2015, 12 F&B outlets, 3 meeting rooms, RS, 180 F&B Team Members)
- Warwick Doha Qatar, Director of Food & Beverage (Opening)
 Jan 2015 July 2015, 5 F&B outlets, 6 meeting rooms, room service and mini bar, 82 Team Members

Ibis Hotel Dubai Al Barsha (Acoor) Food and Beverage Manager Sep 2012 –Sep 2014

- Manage over all F&B Operation, that's includes chef, kitchen staff, and service team of over 50 to provide stellar dining experiences to high-profile customers.
- Oversee administrative tasks, including bookkeeping, training, equipment and food ordering, maintenance, and other needs as they arise.
- Maintain communication with management staff of hotel and corporate directors.
- Prepare annual and monthly budgets, cost analysis, employee performance reviews, and additional quarterly reports.
- Interact daily with hotel and dining guests to promote brand and accept feedback.
- Reporting to the cluster General Manager
- Full responsibility for mystery guest, hygiene, ISO and brand standard audits.
- Certified Acoor trainer.

RAMADA RESORT BY WYNDHAM (Formerly Warwick hotel Dead Sea - JORDAN) Food and Beverage Manager (Pre-opening)

Jan 2012 – Sep 2012

- Manage all F&B and day-to-day operations within budgeted guidelines and to the highest standards
- Preserve excellent levels of internal and external customer service
- Design exceptional menus, purchase goods and continuously make necessary improvements
- Identify customers' needs and respond proactively to all of their concern.
- Lead F&B team by attracting, recruiting, training and appraising talented personnel
- Establish targets, KPI's, schedules, policies and procedures
- Provide a two-way communication and nurture an ownership environment with emphasis in motivation and teamwork

Double Tree By Hilton (Aqaba - JORDAN) Assistant Food and Beverage Manager (Pre-opening)

Jan 2011 -Jan 2012

- Assist in the day to day operations of the Food & Beverage Division, ensuring all service standards are followed
- Execute the delivery of all Food & Beverage promotions and new menus; creating a destination of choice for both hotel and external guests
- Assist and guide the Food & Beverage department achieve their financial and operational targets
- Adhere to the annual budget and administer it in a fiscally responsible manner

REFERENCES

Available on request.

- Monitor control of food, beverage, labour and operating expenses throughout the F&B division
- Monitor all guest service standards, constantly seeking ways to improve product and service as well as increase volumes and profits

Kempinski Hotels, Restaurant Manager

Oct 2006 to Jan 2011

- Apr 2010 Jan 2011 Djibouti Palace Kempinski (Djibouti)
- Managing the all day dining restaurant in the hotel with capacity of 300 Seats, serving international buffet breakfast, lunch and dinner, Room service, mini bar and High standard unique fine dining.
- Total of 112 team members directly reporting to me.
- Responsible of achievement of an average \$14.5M
 Oct 2006 Apr 2010 Kempinski Hotel Ishtar (Dead sea Jordan)
 Restaurant Manager (Pre-opening)
 Key Responsibilities:
- In the preopening stage, started as a Banqueting supervisor for about 5 months after which been moved to assistant restaurant manager Managing the main dining restaurant in the hotel for 6 months. Gradually promoted to restaurant manager for the hotel signature Italian restaurant.
- Total of 48 team members directly reporting to me.
- Responsible of achievement of an average \$10M

SKILLS

Pre-Opening	100%
Customers Experience	100%
Revenue management	100%
Stakeholders management	100%
Audit/ Quality Assurance	100%
Financial Controlling	100%
Project management	100%
Operation management	100%